

## Reza Dwi Utomo

Cikaret, South Bogor, Bogor City, West Java, Indonesia Email: utomorezadwi@gmail.com Website: utomoreza.github.io LinkedIn: /utomorezadwi GitHub: /utomoreza

#### **Summary**

Self-motivated data enthusiast with 4 years of varied experience, such as in independent research in intelligent control and RAMS (Reliability, Availability, Maintainability, and Safety) in manufacture. Skilled in analytical programming, e.g. MATLAB, Python, and R, and eager to enhance proficiency in data analytics, data visualisation, and machine learning by attending a Bootcamp and doing self-learning on MOOC (Massive Open Online Course), e.g. Coursera, DataCamp, Udemy, edX, and lykra.

#### **Formal Education**

# MRes in Railway Systems Integration (upper division 2.1) 08/2016 - 09/2018

University of Birmingham, UK

Core modules: Mathematics as an Engineering Tool, Railway Operations and Control Systems, Railway Traction Systems Design, Railway Control Systems Engineering, Research Skills and Research Environment.

The thesis topic is to develop ATO (Automatic Train Operation) Control Systems with Kalman filter (developed in MATLAB) with a case study of Docklands Light Railway in London. A part of the thesis presented at the IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Rail Transportation (ICIRT) December 2018 in Singapore and published on IEEExplore.

## BEng in Computer Engineering (GPA 3.22) 09/2010 - 08/2015

Diponegoro University

Core modules: artificial intelligence, fuzzy logic, neural networks, real-time operating system (RTOS), microprocessor design, embedded system and distributed embedded system.

Final project topic was to develop fuzzy logic controller (developed in MATLAB/Simulink) able to control transfer function of the train—published in IEEE Conference Proceedings.

#### Technical Skills

**Microsoft Office** 

MATLAB/Simulink

**Python** 

R

SQL

Git/GitHub

Linux (Ubuntu)

HTML

# Very good Very good Very good Very good Very good Intermediate Intermediate Intermediate

Basic

#### **Key Skills**

Problem solving
Effective communication
Teamwork
Interpersonal
Leadership
Analytical thinking
Adaptability

### **Personal Development**

#### **Bootcamp Full Academy Regular – Algoritma**

in progress 01/2020 - 03/2020

A Data Science Bootcamp consisting of two main specializations: Data Visualization Specialization and Machine Learning Specialization.

#### IBM Data Science Professional Certificate - Coursera

in progress

Obtaining a financial aid from Coursera to enrol in this programme. There are 9 courses, i.e. what is data science, open source tools and libraries, methodology, Python, databases, SQL, data visualization, data analysis, IBM Cloud, and machine learning.

**Unsupervised Machine Learning – Algoritma Bootcamp** 

Accomplished 03/2020

One of courses in Machine Learning Specialization at Algoritma Bootcamp which teaches supervised machine learning method and its implementation on R.

#### **Supervised Machine Learning – Algoritma Bootcamp**

Accomplished 02/2020

Three courses in Machine Learning Specialization at Algoritma Bootcamp which teach regression and classification methods of supervised machine learning and their implementation on R.

#### Python for Data Science and AI by IBM – Coursera

Accomplished 02/2020

One of courses in IBM Data Science Professional Certificate which teaches the use of Python for data science and artificial intelligence.

#### Data Visualization Specialization – Algoritma Bootcamp

Accomplished 01/2020

A specialization in Algoritma Bootcamp which teaches the programming for data science using RStudio, data visualization using R base plots and advanced plots, e.g. ggplot and leaflet, and intercactive plots and dynamic dashboard using plotly, flexdashboard, and Shiny dashboard.

#### Data Analyst with Python Career Track - DataCamp

Accomplished 11/2019

A career track with 16 courses (60 hours) focusing on data extraction, data cleaning, data visualization, and statistics using Python and SQL.

And many more.

#### **Experience**

## Engineer Staff – PT Industri Kereta Api (Persero)

02/2019 - 12/2019

**Indonesian Rolling Stock Manufacturer** 

- Assigned to develop a dedicated-for-INKA concept of work for RAMS analysis (Reliability, Availability, Maintainability and Safety) of the rolling stock system.
- As the main contributor for the development of RAMS management process at the company.
- Performing RAMS management Process using EN 50126.
- Performing reliability prediction analysis (developed in MATLAB) on passenger coach whose results are used as a base for managerial decision.

## Junior Expert – Centre of Technology for Transport System and Infrastructure 05/2018 - 01/2019 Agency for the Assessment and Application of Technology (BPPT)

- Involved in the LRT Greater Jakarta project.
- Working in an engineering team collaborated with PT INKA.
- Performing RAMS (Reliability, Availability, Maintainability and Safety) analysis (e.g. FTA, FMEA, MTTR, MTBF, EN 50126) for the systems of doors, HVAC, bogie, wiring and piping connections, and control panels of the rolling stocks.

#### Apprentice - PT Citas Otis Elevator

04/2016 - 07/2016

- Worked as an apprentice at Service Field Department.
- Created official reports from the technical documentation.
- Assisted senior employees in their daily tasks.
- Helped to increase the customers' satisfaction.

# Intern – Centre of Technology for Information & Communication Technology 11/2013 - 12/2013 Agency for the Assessment and Application of Technology (BPPT)

- Worked in an R&D-atmospheric environment which required a weekly progress presentation.
- Managed to have good communications with senior researchers.
- Developed a card reader to read specific data from a smart card based on HY-LPC1788-SDK.
- Applied the modules of the embedded system and RTOS.
- Program written in C++.
- My work was utilised for further developments in national ID cards.